denis.r.cormier@gmail.com

DENIS CORMIER

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Profile

An enthusiastic, bilingual (french, english) computer programmer from Moncton, NB, Canada with over 3 years of work experience with multiple programming languages across several different programming domains.

Skills

Primary Programming Languages

Javascript, AngularJS, NodeJS

MySQL, MongoDB

Scripting (Lua, Python, Bash/Shell, Perl)

C/C++, Java

Tools

Version control (Git, SVN, Hg)

Memory usage/debugging (atop, GDB, Valgrind, Perl debugger)

Jenkins Continuous Integration (CI)

Various

Integrated Development Environments (Atom, Vim, Sublime Text, Eclipse, IntelliJ variants, Visual Studio)

GIMP image manipulation

Experience

Index Exchange Inc. (Formerly known as Casale Media Inc.)

Software Developer in Test II

May 2014 - now

May 2015 - now: Web application transition to AngularJS: mixture of API (NodeJS) and APP (AngularJS/MySQL/MongoDB) testing, localization (multi-language) testing.

May 2014 - May 2015: Testing new features (releases) on the product's front-end (Perl-based GUI + MySQL database).

Supervised and guided new team members, provided test plans and time estimates to assist in project planning.

Solved production/support issues, tested fixes provided by developers.

Coded test suites in Java (Selenium) and Javascript following a transition to a Javascript testing framework.

McAfee Inc.

Software Developer

Sept 2013 - Dec 2013

C++ development work on the McAfee Security Center product: Data collection feature enhancements and Security Center bug fixes

Python scripting for quick prototyping with Google Analytics

 $\label{thm:cooperated} \mbox{ Cooperated with Quality Assurance to thoroughly test the software with manual and automated testing}$

McAfee Inc.

Software Developer

Jan 2013 - Apr 2013

Improved the build speed and frequency of different projects (Jenkins CI system)

Coded a C# application, Windows PowerShell scripts, and Python scripts to automate deploying and testing of various projects

Integrated different team's products in the complete CI process in order to attain high-level goals set by upper management

SurfEasy Inc.

C/C++ Developer

May 2012 - Aug 2012

Researched and implemented file encryption for the Mozilla Firefox browser using Network Security Services and SQLCipher

Worked with C++, Javascript, and XPCOM (Cross Platform Component Object Model) in the Firefox code base

Added and configured builds using the Jenkins CI system

RuggedCom Inc. (Later acquired by Siemens Inc.)

Software Developer

Sept 2011 - Dec 2011

Programmed a vital component to a graphical simulation model that replicates hardware time synchronization behaviour using the SciLab and C programming languages

Completed a series of IEEE1588 time synchronization test cases with real hardware and different traffic loads to validate the simulation's behaviour

Medavie Blue Cross Inc.

IT Programmer

Jan 2011 - Apr 2011

Oracle Forms, Oracle Reports, PL/SQL databases, integration testing

Tennis Canada Inc.

IT Analyst

May 2010 - Aug 2010

Asterisk FreePBX (VoIP system), HTML, PHP, Microsoft Exchange e-mail server

Projects

Various game projects

Visit deniscormier.github.io for more information

Last 2-3 years

Videogame programming (C# scripting for Unity3D game engine, Lua scripting for Love2D game engine)

Tabletop game design

Operating system project in C and Assembly

University course — SE 350: Operating Systems

Jan 2012 - Apr 2012

Useful concepts: memory layout, memory usage, task switching/scheduling, user/kernel level functions

Motorola ARM processor

Keil uVision IDE/tools to build/simulate the project

Education

Univerisity of Waterloo - Waterloo, ON Bachelor of Software Engineering

Sept 2009 - Apr 2014

Honours — Co-operative Program

Denis Cormier — denis.r.cormier@gmail.com

Website-deniscormier.github.io

Code repositories — bitbucket.org/deniscormier